<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./spectra-icon-16x16.png" type="Source">
    <name>Spectra Reader</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Using the jrap-stax library, this node reads mzXML/mzML files into KNIME.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        This node provides the ability to load spectra using the capability
        provided by JRAP-Stax and ProteomeCommons IO frameworks: this provides
        support for many formats, beginning with open-formats eg. mzXML, mzML and MGF.
        
       This node provides two output ports: one for spectra data and summary statistics
       about each spectra eg. number of peaks the other for file-level information eg. 
       instrument software, operator name etc.</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Directory">The folder which contains the spectra files: <tt>.mzXML</tt>, <tt>.xml</tt>,
        <tt>.mgf</tt> or <tt>.mgf.gz</tt> files.
        
        Depending on the format, these files may be validated so see the description of each format below
        for more details. Other files (with different extensions) are skipped. If an
        error occurs during parsing of a file, a warning will be issued and processing will continue
        with remaining files.</option>
        
        <option name="Load Spectra?">If checked, this option causes an additional column to be
        added to the output: with the spectra loaded into it. This can be a very large dataset, it
        is recommended to allocate at least 512MB to knime for this. Be patient with many operations
        as they may take minutes/hours to complete depending on the dataset</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
      
        <outPort index="0" name="Spectra data">Spectral data from files. Missing cell values indicate
        that the parser for the file could not identify the information (it may be unavailable or a bug
        in reading in loading the file format)</outPort>
        
        <outPort index="1" name="Spectra file summary">Summary data from files</outPort>
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
