<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Sequence Aligner</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Performs an alignment, performed by http://jaligner.sourceforge.net of two sequences using the chosen parameters
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>To use this node you can arrange the sequence data two ways:
        <ul>
        	<li>As a single column: the node pairs all the entries in the chosen column, against each other, for alignment (pairwise).</li>
        	<li>As two columns, one sequence per column: no pairing is done. One alignment per row is performed using the two sequences. In this case
        	    the results are appended to the provided columns, existing columns are preserved. If the second column is a collection
        	    column, the first sequence will be aligned with all sequences in the collection: <B>WARNING:</B> this feature 
        	    causes a memory problem with KNIME 2.2 and earlier, be sure to set the memory policy to write to disk
        	    rather than use all your RAM <tt>;-)</tt></li>
        </ul>
        
        You need to choose a scoring matrix (used to rank alternatives based on the amino acids being compared) appropriate to the type of
        sequence being compared. This node does not perform any sequence translation, that must already have been performed.
        
        Although this node supports nucleotide sequences, it does not provide any nucleotide scoring matrices. This node performs no
        sequence conversion. This node supports only nucleotide bases (A, C, G, T), in particular ambiguous base calls are not permitted (currently).
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Score Matrix">Refer to <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/blast/options.shtml">NCBI Blast options</a> for more details</option>
        <option name="Alignment Type">For now, only local alignments are supported.</option>
        <option name="Alignment Format">Format alignment results in FASTA, CLUSTALW or BLAST format</option>
        <option name="Gap Open Penalty">Penalty to apply for creating a new gap in an alignment</option>
        <option name="Gap Extend Penalty">Penalty to apply for extending an existing gap in an alignment</option>
        <option name="Sequences to align...">Determines where sequence data is retrieved from and how alignments are done. The remaining options inform
        the node for key data required to do the alignment ie. which contains contain the sequence and accession data.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input sequences">Sequence data to align</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Alignment Results">Identity, Similarity and Score for the alignments performed</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
