<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
   <name>BioJava Processor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Analyses the specified data using BioJava (see http://www.biojava.org) and produces the result at output. Depending
        on the task chosen, other parameters must be chosen to correctly perform the operation: see below for more details.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node performs numerous convenient tasks using biojava. It is designed to perform many
        operations in a single task, which is commonly needed at the ACPFG.
        
        <p>
        <b>NOTE:</b> The calculations will produce missing values in the results if unknown residues are involved eg. X's in the sequence.
        Fix your sequences if you dont like this behaviour...
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Task">Describes what operation to perform.
	        <ol>
	        <li>Compute hydrophobicity, pI and mass for sequences: performs an average amino acid hydrophobicity calculation, isoelectricpoint and calculates mass in Da (per biojava cookbook). Sequences with unknown residues are skipped</li>
	        <li>Perform Six-Frame nucleotide translation: adds six columns to the input data, one for each frame translation. Excess nucleotides are trimmed to make the sequence a multiple of 3</li>
	        <li>Convert DNA to RNA (Universal translation only): conver0ts DNA sequences to RNA using the universal translation table</li>
	        <li>Convert RNA to Protein Sequence: converts RNA sequences in the specified sequence to Protein sequence</li>
	        <li>Alternate translation of DNA to Protein (all built-in tables): adds 16 columns to the input data, and converts all DNA sequences to protein using every available translation table</li>
	        <li>Computing the frequencies of residues at each position in the input sequence(s). This option will add the user-specified number of columns (up to a maximum) with frequencies of each residue letter in each column</li>
	        </ol>
        </option>
        <option name="Sequence">Select the (string only) column which contains the sequences to be processed by the specified task</option>
        <option name="Sequence Type">This node does <b>not</b> guess the sequence type, it insists you instruct it via this list. The
        chosen task will perform automatic conversion as described above.</option>
        <option name="Maximum Sequence Length">Only relevant to the position-by-residue task. If you are only interested in the first
        few residues in each sequence, set this to the required number of starting residues to avoid un-necessary calculation (and improve speed).</option>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Sequence data">Data to use for the biojava task. Generally, each row is calculated independently although
        this depends on the task.</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="BioJava calculation">The results of the chosen calculation, which are appended to the input data columns</outPort>
        
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
