<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source">
    <name>Mascot Reader</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Using the MascotDatFile open-source java library, this node provides an interface to that, to provide convenient access to MatrixScience Mascot datasets
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node reads a folder containing <a href="http://www.matrixscience.com">Mascot</a> data files and loads them into
        KNIME for further analysis. This node uses the excellent <a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/17203510">Mascotdatfile library</a> to perform the extraction of data.
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Folder">The folder containing the .DAT files, other files (or folders) in this folder will be ignored.</option>
        <option name="Result Selection">There are three choices: 
          <ul>
            <li><b>All</b>: Every peptide which is assigned to a given spectra (query) is reported</li>
            <li><b>Best only</b>: Only peptides which are considered to be the best match, by Mascot, to the spectra is reported</li>
            <li><b>Identity Threshold Confidence</b> All hits over the chosen Identity threshold are reported, regardless of which spectra they
            were assigned to</li>
          </ul>
        </option>
        
        <option name="Identity Threshold Confidence">Only peptide hits considered within this value will be reported. 0.05 in this field
        corresponds to a 95% CI, which is what you should use unless your sure of what this means. Remember this is a peptide-level
        confidence measure and not protein-level (which is generally much lower due to multiple possible matches for a peptide to a protein)</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Mascot Results">Contains the peptide and protein assignments identified by Mascot for the specified .DAT files</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
