<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>WU-BLAST Accessor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Performs a WU-BLAST 2.0 (incl. gaps) with the chosen parameters using the EBI webservices.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Performs a WU-BLAST with the chosen parameters using the EBI webservices.  
        More details can be found at <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/Tools/webservices/">Webservices@EBI</a>
        
        <p><b>NOTE</b>: this node restricts performance to limits well-within
        those required by EBI:
        <ol>
           <li>No more than 25 BLAST jobs will be submitted to EBI per user/per-node at one time</li>
           <li>20 second wait for the jobs to be processed (mandatory)</li>
           <li>Checking to see if all jobs currently submitted have completed and then submitting the next batch. This checking 
               linearly backs-off the longer the job is taking.</li>
        </ol>
        </p>
        
      
        <b>WARNING:</b> Users bypassing these constraints will find EBI ban them (and probably their entire organization) from accessing the service.
         
        <p><b>WARNING:</b> Data passed to this node is subject to EBI's terms and conditions. Confidential sequence data should not be given
        to this node, unless you are sure of what you are doing.</p>
        
        <p>All input columns are output to each port, to preserve existing information. The node will fail if the column names required by this
        node already exist.</p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Column containing blast sequences">Nucleotide/Amino Acid sequence. Must be correct for the BLAST program chosen (no sequence conversion takes place).</option>
        <option name="Sequence Type">Choose the appropriate type of sequence for the sequence column. Currently, all rows must be of this type or results will be undefined.</option>
        <option name="Email address">Email address is required by EBI should there be a problem with the jobs. This must be a valid email address or you risk being banned.</option>
    	<option name="Databases">All EBI WU-BLAST Databases will appear in this list. The entire UniProt (reviewed+not reviewed) is the default</option>
    	<option name="BLAST Program">Choose the appropriate blast variant for the type of sequence. This node does not convert sequence data.</option>
    	<option name="Scoring Matrix">BLOSUM62 is a good default for protein sequence, identity for nucleotide sequence</option>
    	<option name="Filters">Low complexity filter: choose 'seg' for protein, 'DUST' for nucleotide</option>
    	<option name="Sensitivity">Choose the <i>ktup</i> parameter (higher sensitivity takes longer at EBI)</option>
    	<option name="Sort criteria">Kinda useless, given KNIME's capabilities, but provided for completeness with EBI</option>
    	<option name="Statistics">Distribution desired for results</option>
    	<option name="Number of reported alignments">Provide the best-50 (by default) alignments in the results - per sequence</option>
    	<option name="Number of reported scores">Provide the best-50 (by default) scores in the results - per sequence</option>
    	<option name="Maximum Expectation Value">Do not report results above the specified E-value for a given sequence</option>
    	<option name="EBI Batch Size">the number of concurrent BLASTS which may be outstanding at any time. Maximum 25.</option>
  		<option name="Save image summary?">In the first output port, a column with a visual depiction of the blast hits will be shown if checked.
  		May slow down the performance of the node, so it is off by default (cells will be blank)</option>
 	</fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input sequence data">Provides the sequence column which is to be blasted. Other columns will be copied to the output.</inPort>
        
       
        <outPort index="0" name="Raw results">Provides the EBI jobID, XML and graphical summary (iff enabled) of results for each BLAST sequence.</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Formatted results">Provides a select view of results: with key columns only. Useful for further KNIME processing, where
        only the key information is required (E-value, accession etc.). Other columns will be copied to the output.</outPort>
        
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
