<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Minimum Protein List</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Uses Integer Linear Programming, via the GLPK toolkit, to implement a minimum set cover algorithm
        which is then used to produce a minumum protein list. 
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Uses Integer Linear Programming, via the <a href="http://www.gnu.org/s/glpk/">GLPK toolkit</a>, 
        to implement a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Set_cover_problem">minimum set cover algorithm</a> which is then used to produce a minimum protein list. the node expects two columns:
        <ul>
        	<li>A column containing the protein ID (eg. uniprot accession). Only one row may contain a given accession</li>
        	<li>A column containing the comma-separated peptides attributed to that accession (there must be at least one).
        	This can be done using node group-by node with the concatenate option for the peptide sequence column</li>
        </ul>
        This node will answer the question: what is the smallest number of proteins which can explain the observed
        peptides?
        
        <p>
        <b>Note:</b> this node may not produce an optimal answer, at the moment this node does not tell you
        whether the minimum set has been produced (but that should be fixed soon!). This node treats all proteins
        as having the same weight, which for some experiments may not be desirable. This node can only be used
        on systems with GLPK installed.
        </p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Peptide Sequence">Select the column which provides a comma-separated 
        list of peptides observed for a given protein (row)</option>
        <option name="Accession">Select the column which provides the protein ID (must
        be unique across the input table for correct results)</option>
        <option name="GPLK Solver executable">Specify the glpsol.exe file path. GLPK v4.4 was used with this node, other versions
        may work, but have not been tested</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Peptide-Protein table">An input table with each row identifying a single
        protein and the peptides matched to it</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Peptide-Protein table">Same data with an additional column
        for whether the protein is part of the approximate minimal set</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
