<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Spectra Quality Scorer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Implements the 'Xrea' algorithm as described in the paper "Quality Assessment of 
        Tandem Mass Spectra Based on Cumulative Intensity Normalization". This node also provides a second column for
        adjustment of scores where several peaks dominate the spectra.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Implements the 'Xrea' algorithm as described in the paper <a href="http://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/pr0603248">Quality Assessment of 
        Tandem Mass Spectra Based on Cumulative Intensity Normalization</a>. This node provides an additional two columns:
        <ul>
        	<li>an Xrea calculation which tries to be faithful to the method described in the paper</li>
        	<li>an adjusted Xrea value computed when several peaks dominate the spectra. The approach adopted is to re-score the spectra
        	after removing the dominant peaks. The user may set the thresholds for performing adjustment by configuring the node</li>
        </ul>
        This node may implement other algorithms at a future date.</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Spectra Column">Column containing spectra to evaluate for quality score. 
        This node can only process one spectra column at this time, though this may change in future.</option>
        <option name="Dominant Peak Score Adjustment">If you have spectra which are being too highly scored because several peaks
        dominate the spectrum, consider this option. Here you can specify calculation of an adjusted Xrea score which removes the dominant
        peaks and scores the remainder. You can choose how much of the TIC (as a fraction) and the maximum number of peaks which must meet
        the TIC fraction for adjustment to take place.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input spectra">Data with Spectra column</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Output Spectra &amp; Quality">Appended Spectra Quality scores</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
   
</knimeNode>
