<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Phobius Accessor</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Takes a list of sequences and appends the results of Phobius webservice invocations (text only for now) to the output port
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node provides access to the <a href="http://www.ebi.ac.uk/tools/webservices/">Phobius webservice</a>
         at the European Bioinformatics Institute (EBI). The node is designed to access EBI slowly, to ensure EBI computer's
         are not overloaded, which is not user-configurable. Raw results and decoded results are provided to give the
         user control over what results to use for further computation</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Protein Sequence column">The column which contains the protein sequence (amino acid) to use for each phobius search. This
        data is not modified in any way prior to being sent to EBI.</option>
        
        <option name="Email Address">The user of the node must provide a valid email address in case EBI want to contact you
        to report a problem with the jobs you submit. <b>WARNING:</b> Failure to provide a valid address may result in your computer or
        your entire network being banned from EBI.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Protein Sequences">Input table including a column of protein sequences</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Phobius Results">Output data, all input columns are preserved but with the phobius columns added. This node will fail if there are columns already
         existing with the same names as what the node wants to add, an error will be issued.</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
    
</knimeNode>
